去 determine 出來的一個一個 value speed
啊，是一個... 啊...
就是說他用數學算出來的一個最保守的一個... 一個安全速，一個一個 event speed
啊，就發生 event。那這個是還沒有加入 in-service allowance 的部分
好，那剛剛的那一個，我們的 Liftoff speed 是 1.1 倍的 Vmu
All-engine 是 1.1 倍。然後是 One engine operate 是 1.05
好
好，然後再來就是 Minimum Control Speed，Vmc with critical engine operate
那你們這邊可以，基本上，它你們小飛機的 Vmc 就是 VmcA
那 OK，好，你們沒有 VmcG
原因是因為 Certification 沒有 requirement
好，那 Minimum Stall Speed 呢，是你們都知道 Rotation speed
那 V1 呢，是 Takeoff action speed during the takeoff, when the pilot must take the first action to stop
while within the accelerate-stop distance, such as applying brakes or reducing the thrust.
Also the minimum speed, uh, following an failure of a critical engine at the VEF
at which the pilot can continue the takeoff and achieve the required height above the takeoff surface
within the takeoff distance. 好
那 V2 是 Takeoff Safety Speed
啊，那 frequently a speed that allow for the optimum... uh...
V2 min 是 Minimum takeoff safety speed, V2 min
好，那 Vs0 是 Stall speed or minimum steady flight speed in the landing configuration
Vs1 是 for, uh, the stall speed, obtained in a specified configuration
所以是，你可以有 Flap 1 的 Vs1，你也可以有 Flap Up 的那個什麼 Vs1
對，OK 嗎？好
那一般來講，我們的 Vs1 是指 Clean configuration。一般
好，那 VmcA 是 Minimum control speed in the air
那這個通常我們在記 VmcA 的時候就是什麼？Rudder pedal 不超過多少磅？150 磅
Maximum bank angle allowed 是多少？5 度。最大的 bank angle
然後，但是，然後再來就是 maintain directional control, heading change 不可以超過幾度？20 度
好。好
Vxse 是 Best Angle of Climb OEI, Vyse 是 Best Rate of Climb OEI, 那 Vref 是 Reference Speed for landing
at the speed of a final approach, which is adjust to the normal approach speed factor. 好，那 Vsse... (不確定內容)
好，這部分大概就這樣
好，接下來我們就要談斷到... uh... reference speed
好，Reference speed 的部分
(操作電腦搜尋中)
好，那我們接下來看的是，剛剛我們 Takeoff Speed 大都看完了喔
那我們接下來看 Landing Speed 的部分
AIM
(投影片展示：Instrument Approach Procedures)
Has the following category limits:
1. Category A: Speed less than 91 knots.
2. Category B: Speed 91 knots or more but less than 121 knots.
(教官翻閱文件中)
Aircraft Approach Category - A grouping of aircraft based on a speed of 1.3 times the stall speed
in the landing configuration at maximum gross landing weight.
(教官翻閱文件中)
好，我們先來講在 Approach 的部分好，在 FAA 如果你們有考這個 Instrument Commercial 的話
雖然我時間說不用背喔，但是如果有的話你可以 refer 到 Approach 的部分
在第八章吧
(教學結束)